<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CVXR</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CVXR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Examples</title>
      <link>/post/cvxr_examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cvxr_examples/</guid>
      <description>Many of the examples here have been ported over from the CVXPY site, although we have several others too.
Basic Examples  Introduction Catenary Problem Isotonic Regression Near Isotonic and Near Convex Regression Direct Standardization   References  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Isotonic and Near Convex Regression</title>
      <link>/post/near-isotonic-and-near-convex-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/near-isotonic-and-near-convex-regression/</guid>
      <description>Given a set of data points \(y \in {\mathbf R}^m\), R. J. Tibshirani, Hoefling, and Tibshirani (2011) fit a nearly-isotonic approximation \(\beta \in {\mathbf R}^m\) by solving
$$ \[\begin{array}{ll} \underset{\beta}{\mbox{minimize}} &amp;amp; \frac{1}{2}\sum_{i=1}^m (y_i - \beta_i)^2 + \lambda \sum_{i=1}^{m-1}(\beta_i - \beta_{i+1})_+, \end{array}\] $$
where \(\lambda \geq 0\) is a penalty parameter and \(x_+ =\max(x,0)\). This can be directly formulated in cvxr. As an example, we use global warming data from the Carbon Dioxide Information Analysis Center (CDIAC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Catenary Problem</title>
      <link>/post/catenary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/catenary/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A chain with uniformly distributed mass hangs from the endpoints \((0,1)\) and \((1,1)\) on a 2-D plane. Gravitational force acts in the negative \(y\) direction. Our goal is to find the shape of the chain in equilibrium, which is equivalent to determining the \((x,y)\) coordinates of every point along its curve when its potential energy is minimized.
This is the famous catenary problem.
 A Discrete Version To formulate as an optimization problem, we parameterize the chain by its arc length and divide it into \(m\) discrete links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Direct Standardization</title>
      <link>/post/direct-standardization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/direct-standardization/</guid>
      <description>Consider a set of observations \((x_i,y_i)\) drawn non-uniformly from an unknown distribution. We know the expected value of the columns of \(X\), denoted by \(b \in {\mathbf R}^n\), and want to estimate the true distribution of \(y\). This situation may arise, for instance, if we wish to analyze the health of a population based on a sample skewed toward young males, knowing the average population-level sex, age, etc. The empirical distribution that places equal probability \(1/m\) on each \(y_i\) is not a good estimate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isotonic Regression</title>
      <link>/post/isotonic-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/isotonic-regression/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Isotonic regression is regression with monotonic constraints. There are several packages in R to fit isotonic regression models. In this example, we consider isotone which uses a pooled-adjacent-violators algorithm (PAVA) and active set methods to perform the fit.
 Pituitary Data Example We will use data from the isotone package (see de Leeuw, Hornik, and Mair (2009)) on the size of pituitary fissures for 11 subjects between 8 and 14 years of age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CVXR Functions</title>
      <link>/post/cvxr_functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cvxr_functions/</guid>
      <description>Functions Here we describe the functions that can be applied to cvxr expressions. cvxr uses the function information in this section and the Disciplined Convex Programming tools to mark expressions with a sign and curvature.
Operators The infix operators +, -, *, / are treated as functions. + and - are affine functions. * and / are affine in cvxr because expr1*expr2 is allowed only when one of the expressions is constant and expr1/expr2 is allowed only when expr2 is a scalar constant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convex Optimization in R</title>
      <link>/post/cvxr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cvxr/</guid>
      <description>What is cvxr? cvxr is an R package that provides an object-oriented modeling language for convex optimization, similar to CVX, CVXPY, YALMIP, and Convex.jl. It allows the user to formulate convex optimization problems in a natural mathematical syntax rather than the restrictive standard form required by most solvers. The user specifies an objective and set of constraints by combining constants, variables, and parameters using a library of functions with known mathematical properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>/post/cvxr_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cvxr_intro/</guid>
      <description>Consider a simple linear regression problem where it is desired to estimate a set of parameters using a least squares criterion.
We generate some synthetic data where we know the model completely, that is
\[ Y = X\beta + \epsilon \]
where \(Y\) is a \(100\times 1\) vector, \(X\) is a \(100\times 10\) matrix, \(\beta = -4,\ldots ,-1, 0, 1, \ldots 5\) and \(\epsilon \sim N(0, 1).\)
set.seed(123) n &amp;lt;- 100 p &amp;lt;- 10 beta &amp;lt;- -4:5 # beta is just -4 through 5.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>